[racket swooshes]
[pants]
[boy 1] Taiki just...
[boy 2] Won a match against Haryu.
[panting]
And so, until then, don't lose.
[exclaims softly]
Right!
[Taiki] Was I
holding my own against Haryu?
[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
EPISODE 8
SCORE!
[alarm sounds]
[alarm stops]
[sighs]
[birds chirping]
[Chinatsu] Here we go.
[instrumental music playing]
Good morning.
Good morning!
Well, aren't you up early.
Oh, hi, Chinatsu. Good morning
I just couldn't sit still.
I kept thinking I'd be super nervous
and tense before the tournament.
CALISTHENICS
But now that it's finally today,
I'm psyched.
[exclaims softly]
- Let me join you.
- Huh?
[Taiki] She's so cute.
You're playing doubles today, right?
Um, yes! The singles matches are tomorrow.
How many of you can make it
into nationals, then?
One pair for doubles,
and two players for singles.
Those are pretty tough odds.
Your situation is kinda the same, no?
[Chinatsu] Basketball's
a team sport, though.
Well, I heard that Kagohara
is looking good this year.
Yeah, we're playing them
in the finals, so we have to win.
The finals are tomorrow, right?
[Chinatsu] Yep. Tomorrow.
Already tomorrow.
Um, Chinatsu.
After tomorrow,
could I ask you one question?
I still want to know
why she said she was jealous.
- You don't wanna ask now?
- Nuh-uh.
Okay. Is it all right
if I ask you a question instead?
Huh?
Does badminton club
have any chants you do for each other?
"Score one more"?
'Kay, got it.
Then score... one more!
Sure!
[chuckles]
Wow, those exercises refreshed me.
[Taiki] Does she have to keep
making my heart race like that?
SHITAO SPORTS PARK GYMNASIUM
ONE SCORE AT A TIME
- [players playing]
- [all cheering]
DAUNTLESS COURAGE
HEART, SKILL, STRENGTH - PLAY FOR THE WIN!
FLY - EVERY SHOT COUNTS
Dang, it's hot.
It's only mid-June
and it's already scorching.
I dread the rest of the summer.
We can't open the windows, either.
[Taiki] But this atmosphere...
does add to the tournament feel,
so I don't really mind.
KENGO HARYU - TAIKI INOMATA
(EIMEI)
SHOTA HYODO - YUKI TATEYAMA
(SAJIKAWA)
[Haryu] Okay. I should get going.
Where you off to?
EIMEI
Come with me and see.
This should be a good spot.
[Taiki] We came here to watch a match.
But whose?
[announcer on PA] This is
the call for match number 21.
SAJIKAWA
Hyodo and Tateyama
of Sajikawa High School.
It's the Hyodo-Tateyama pair!
Their aura is on a different level.
They're huge!
[Taiki] So that's Hyodo.
The player Haryu's never beaten.
Oh, hey. If it isn't Haryu.
You come all this way just to lose?
Hey, thanks in advance.
For returning the trophy
that we'll be leaving with today.
I gave it to the organizers, but...
Poor guy, he doesn't get it.
[Tateyama] Hyodo, let's get ready.
Take a good look,
and come up with some counterstrategies.
[Taiki] He's just
oozing confidence, isn't he?
[Haryu] That's 'cause
he's actually that good.
Like if this were baseball,
I could only throw curveballs.
Whereas Hyodo throws curveballs
and killer fastballs.
If we had stats like characters
in video games,
technique, agility, endurance, and speed...
The only player to be maxed out
in all of those stats...
would be him.
Wow, he's in a league of his own.
Seeing that would make anyone wanna quit.
[boy 1] I feel bad
for the kids playing them.
They probably would've gone farther
had they avoided this matchup.
[boy 2] Now it's just a matter
of if they can score any points.
[boy 1] They might be playing
against future Olympians,
so that's a cool memory at least.
Wow, he hit it that way?
I would've done the opposite!
Oh, all that,
and the smash still went too high.
I wonder what would've happened
with a cross-court instead.
Now I wanna try that!
Well, that's easier said than done, Taiki.
[Taiki grunts]
- But now we know what we're up against.
- Huh?
Let's go warm up.
Sounds good.
I think I'll get Nishida to film us.
[Taiki] But he seemed pretty down
after getting eliminated.
[announcer on PA] Match number 28.
Huh?
[snoring]
[Taiki] They dropped their wallet.
Oh. I should tell them.
Even if they are sleeping.
Hello?
Huh?
I think that your wallet
fell out of your pocket.
What? Oh.
I really appreciate it.
[Taiki] No worries.
[Haryu] Taiki, we're up!
Coming!
- See you.
- Mm.
[Yusa] He seemed like a nice guy.
There you are.
Sleeping in random places again, Yusa?
Coach was looking for you.
Huh? Oh.
I'll be right there.
SAJIKAWA
[Yusa] But badminton
isn't a sport for nice guys.
SHITAO SPORTS PARK GYMNASIUM
- [boy] Yusa.
- Hm?
What are you doing
with that racket string?
We need to go cheer on Hyodo and Tateyama.
Don't just sit around.
You should really be watching
and learning from your seniors.
[Yusa] Well, that's a given.
They're up against Haryu from Eimei,
so it'll be a fun match to watch.
DAUNTLESS COURAGE
So what did we miss?
Still game one.
Sixteen-nine.
It's looking like it'll be an easy win.
[boy 1] It's too bad for Haryu.
He's talented! But he's never won
an official match against Hyodo.
If he'd been with us, he and Hyodo
could've teamed up and gone to nationals.
[grunts]
[boy 2] And his teammate
is a first year, right?
They're down by almost double the points.
I don't think the score
reflects their skill, though.
What?
Their execution
on the court isn't that bad.
They're keeping the rally going.
They just have to find
a way to follow through.
- [grunts]
- [boy] He returned it!
Our team keeps pressing them,
but Haryu isn't backing down!
[inhales] Nice one, Taiki.
Thanks!
You got it!
Nice, Haryu!
[boy] You know, you're right.
That first-year is pretty tough.
His aim may not be perfect,
but his shots always go over the net.
And Haryu's got his back.
[both grunting]
[Nishida] Wow! Nice one, Haryu!
Keep attacking!
[exciting music playing]
[referee] Out!
Aw! That was close,
but they lost the first game.
[Eimei player] You guys got this!
[referee] Change ends.
[Taiki] Damn it.
Just when we were catching up, too.
I need to be landing those shots.
Get outta your head.
The next game, let's win.
Let's win!
[Sajikawa player 1] That was close, dude!
His smash was looking good.
[Sajikawa player 2]
If he starts landing shots like that
in the second game,
we might be in trouble.
[footsteps]
[door opens]
Oh. Hello there.
Oh, there you are, Chinatsu! Welcome back.
Congratulations on the finals.
- Fingers are crossed for tomorrow!
- Thank you!
I'm just running to the convenience store.
[Chinatsu] Um...
How did Taiki do today?
[Yukiko] It seems he lost.
[Chinatsu] Tai... ki...
He's asleep.
Reminding him he's a first-year,
or that he still has singles...
probably won't comfort him right now.
MAKE SURE MY SMASHES SCORE!!
It's just that...
[gasps]
[sighs]
How could I forget.
You're not the type
to let this get you down.
[Yukiko] Taiki!
[groans softly]
Sleeping there like that
will affect your performance tomorrow.
[Taiki] You're right.
I think I was dreaming about Chinatsu.
[gasps]
MAKE SURE MY SMASHES SCORE!!
AND I'LL MAKE SURE I MAKE MY SHOTS!
[gasps]
Even her handwriting moves me.
SHITAO SPORTS PARK GYMNASIUM
[Haryu] Listen, Taiki.
You'll face me in the finals.
But to get there, you'll have
to take down Hyodo in the semis.
We may've lost in doubles, but you--
I got this.
All I need to do is play my best.
And first is round one.
[Haryu] After losing doubles,
and seeing what he's up against,
I thought he'd be more nervous.
But that's Taiki for you.
[Taiki] I want to win.
Even if I'm up against
one of the best in the country,
I'm giving it my all.
I'll put everything I have
into the match till it's over.
I bet that Chinatsu
is playing the same way, too.
- [shuttlecock thudding]
- That's why.
[referee] In!
Game.
Twenty-one eleven, twenty-one thirteen.
Yusa of Sajikawa High School wins.
Game.
Twenty-one eleven, twenty-one thirteen.
Yusa of Sajikawa High School wins.
[all cheering]
[Taiki] Huh?
It's already over?
Thank you for the match.
And thank you for refereeing.
Winning player, can you please sign here?
[referee] His handwriting sucks!
[Taiki] Oh, right. Since I lost...
I have to umpire now.
PLAY FOR THE WIN!
[Hina] Wait.
It's over?
[Kyo] Hina.
Hi, Miss Gymnast!
Oh, hi, Kyo. So...
you all still have matches, right?
Like, a round-robin in each division?
Taiki is only just getting warmed up?
No, that's not how it works.
But... Taiki...
He worked so hard.
You're an athlete, too, you get it.
Tournaments end like that.
Being able to play
at the top of your game here is a skill.
You don't win any points
just because you tried, or worked at it.
That's sports.
- [Taiki] At least say something.
- [gasps softly]
Or were you sneaking up on me like always?
As if I would ever be so childish!
You are, all the time.
Should you be speaking to me that way?
When I've brought you something special?
Wait.
Don't tell me you made your special bento.
That was the plan, but I was feeling lazy,
so I brought you snacks.
Oh, thank goodness. No food poisoning.
- What was that, Taiki?
- Uh...
I said I was thankful.
Sorry you came all this way
with these, and for what?
Don't worry about it.
I have to say, sometimes I thought
getting to nationals was gonna be
pretty hard for me at my level.
But I was hoping a big goal would push me.
It made me feel like
I just had to keep going, no matter what.
I do think that I've gotten better.
And then after I won
the game against Haryu,
I actually started to think there
was a chance I could make it to nationals.
At the end of the day,
I suppose I just wasn't
being honest with myself.
This is good.
Real good.
[Hina] You never lose sight of your goals.
And you give it everything you have.
That's what's great about you, Taiki.
[intense music playing]
[grunts]
[cheering]
Another year
of Sajikawa totally dominating.
That Hyodo's a force to be reckoned with.
[organizer] Haryu put up a good fight,
and he's secured a spot in nationals
as a second-year.
Once Hyodo moves on next year,
Haryu's gonna be top dog.
[reporter] Don't forget about Yusa
from Sajikawa. He's one to watch.
He may have lost to Hyodo
in this tournament, but played well.
Can't wait to see where he goes from here.
[gasps]
[referee] Game!
[announcer on PA] The winner
is Hyodo from Sajikawa High School.
[all cheering]
I am going to annihilate him at nationals.
[grunts angrily]
[boy] That face
does not scream "runner-up".
It's gotta be tough losing to Hyodo.
What?
Hey, let's get some food.
Wait, where's Taiki?
I was going to grab a bite
to eat with him.
He went home.
I think he's probably super bummed out.
Yeah, I bet.
SHOPPING DISTRICT
[emotional music playing]
[Taiki] I can't let this
get me down too long.
I have to snap out of it,
and get back to work.
I gotta do something. Practice!
I'll go for it again next year.
INOMATA
I am only a first-year.
I've got two whole chances left.
PREFECTURAL QUALIFIERS
Even if Chinatsu's not here anymore.
[Yukiko] Hey! You are on a roll, Chinatsu!
We're so proud!
I am so, so happy for you!
Count on me to cheer you on.
We've gotta have you strong for nationals!
We'll have a feast tonight.
[Chinatsu] Thank you so much.
[Taiki] That's great.
Chinatsu made it through to nationals.
That's great.
Amazing. That's amazing!
She said she would,
and she did it. That's...
really cool.
Even though...
even though...
[runs, pants]
I lost.
[closing theme song playing]